John Alden Carpenter Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1904-1951 (Box 4-9, 12)
  - Manuscripts, 1913-1949 (Box 4-8, 12)
    - Endlose Liebe, Holograph piano-vocal score; [2] p.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 3, item 41)
    - Endlose Liebe, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; [2] p. (Box-folder 4/27)
    - Endlose Liebe, Copyist's piano-vocal score; [2] p. (Box-folder 4/28)
    - Fanfarette - Berceuse for Richard, Holograph full score; [1] l.; At end: For Halina, Artur and Richard. God bless you all. J.A.C. Hobe Sound, Fla., Feb. '45; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 1, item 14)
    - The faun. Act II, p. 36; Act III, p. 32; Suffragette March, Holograph piano score; 13 p. (Box-folder 5/1)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 5, item 59)
    - The faun. Act II, p. 36; Act III, p. 32; Suffragette March, Holograph piano score; 20 p. (Box-folder 5/1)
    - The faun. Act II (Page 36), Holograph full score; [13] p.; On p. 1: "The Heart of Nature" (Box-folder 5/2)
    - The faun. Suffragette March, Holograph full score; 4 p. (Box-folder 5/2)
    - The faun. [Untitled], Holograph full score; 11 p.; On p. 1, with incipit: Faun theme (Box-folder 5/2)
    - The faun. Act III (Page 32), Holograph full score; 11 p. (Box-folder 5/2)
    - The faun. [Untitled], Holograph full score, incomplete; [1], 83 p. (Box-folder 5/2a)
    - The faun. [Untitled], Copyist's first violin part; [3] p. (Box-folder 5/2a)
    - Fog wraiths, Holograph piano-vocal score; 3 p. (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Four seasons, Holograph sketches; [23 p.] (Box-folder 5/4)
    - From hill and plain, Holograph sketches; [4] p. (Box-folder 5/5)
    - From a tree-top, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; 3 p.; Title crossed out (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Gentle Jesus, meek and mild, Holograph piano-vocal score; [2], [1] p.; Includes 3 photocopies (2 positive, 1 negative). (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Gitanjali; arr., Holograph full score; [72] p.; Arranged for orchestra; acc. originally for piano; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 3, item 42)
    - Gitanjali; arr., Copyist's manuscript of full score, with emendations in composer's hand; [82] p.; see ML96.C274
    - Gitanjali; arr., Holograph full score of revised arr.; At end: Aug. 15th '34. Chicago, Pride's Crossing.; see ML96.C274
    - Gitanjali. No. 6; fragment, Holograph sketch, pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 5/7a)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 5, item 66)
    - Go, lovely rose, Holograph piano-vocal score; [4] p. (Box-folder 5/8)
    - The green river, Holograph piano-vocal score; [4] p. (Box-folder 5/9)
    - The green river, Holograph piano-vocal score, incomplete; [2] p. (Box-folder 5/10)
    - The heart's country, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; [2] p. (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Her voice, Holograph piano-vocal score; [5] p. (Box-folder 5/12)
    - The hermit crab, Holograph piano-vocal score; [2] p.; At end: January 1929; Includes positive and negative photostats (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Highwaymen, Holograph piano-vocal score; 2 p.; On p. 1: May 7th, '16; Deposit of the National Federation of Music Clubs; see ML96.N22C
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 56)
    - The home road, Holograph full score; 4 p.; Orchestration by Eric DeLamarter.; Laid in: printed piano-vocal score (1 p.); see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 49)
    - The home road, Arranger's manuscript; [6] p.; Arranged by Eric DeLamarter; see ML96.D42
    - How to dance, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; [3] p. (Box-folder 5/14)
    - If, Holograph piano-vocal score; [2] p.; At end: Dec. '34 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Il pleure dans mon coeur, Holograph piano-vocal sketch; [3] p. (Box-folder 5/16)
    - Il pleure dans mon coeur, Copyist's piano-vocal score; 5 p. (Box-folder 5/16)
    - Impromptu, Holograph piano score; [3] p. (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Jazz boys See also: Shake your brown feet, honey, Reproduced from holograph piano-vocal score; [3] p.; Bound with: Midnight Nan ([3] p.), The cryin' blues ([2] p.), and Shake your brown feet, honey ([4] p.) (Box-folder 5/18)
    - Jazz orchestra pieces, Reproduced from holograph scores; bound volume (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Khaki Sammy, Holograph piano-vocal score; [3] p.; On p. 1, at top: August 20, '17; On p. 1, at bottom: (Copyright applied for by John A. Carpenter) 8/20/17 (Box-folder 5/20)
    - Krazy Kat; a jazz-pantomime, Holograph full score, revised version; 58 p.; Scenario by George Herriman. 1939.; At end: Dec. '39; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 1, item 15)
    - Krazy Kat; arr., Holograph piano-vocal score; [15] p.; Arranged for voice and piano; On p. [1]: May-Sept. 1921; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 1, item 16)
    - Krazy Kat; arr., Holograph piano-vocal score, revised version; 15 p.; At end: Jan. 2nd-12th-'40; see ML96.C274
    - Land of mine, Holograph piano-vocal score and sketch; [1], [1] p.; On p. 1: Aug. 4 '17 (Box-folder 5/21)
    - Little fly, Holograph piano-vocal score; [4] p. (Box-folder 5/22)
    - Little heathen boys, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; [2] p. (Box-folder 5/23)
    - Little heathen boys, Printer's proofs; [4] p.; Not filmed (Box-folder 5/24)
    - Little nigger, Holograph piano score; [3] p.; On p. 1: April 9th '16 (Box-folder 5/25)
    - The little prayers of I, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; [2] p. (Box-folder 5/26)
    - The little turtle, Holograph piano-vocal score in blue ink; [2] p.; On p. 1: November 1926 (Box-folder 5/27)
    - Love in the valley, Holograph score, incomplete (vocal part only); [2] p. (Box-folder 5/28)
    - The marshes of Glynn, Holograph piano-vocal score and sketches; [4] p. (Box-folder 6/1)
    - May the maiden, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; [3] p. (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Memory, Holograph piano-vocal sketch; [4] p. (Box-folder 6/3)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 5, item 65)
    - Menuet, Holograph full score; 4 p.; On p. 1: Jan. 1923 (Box-folder 6/4)
    - Menuet, Holograph instrumental parts; 1 p., 1 p., 1 p. (Box-folder 6/4)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 5, item 67)
    - Midnight Nan See also: Jazz boys, Holograph piano-vocal score; 3 p.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 43)
    - Miniature, Holograph score for violin & piano; 3 p. (Box-folder 6/5)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 5, item 63)
    - Mistress mine, Reproduced from copyist's piano-vocal score; 2 p. (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Morning fair, Holograph piano-vocal score; 5 p.; At end: Jan. '35; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 44)
    - Morning fair, Ozalid of holograph score; 5 p. (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Mountain! Mountain!, Copyist's piano-vocal score in blue ink; [2] p.; On p. 1: November 1926 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Mountain! Mountain!, Copyist's piano-vocal score in black ink, with typed text; [2] p. (Box-folder 6/8)
    - The music doctor's blues, Holograph score for violin and piano; 3 p.; On p. 1: June 14th - '28; At end: We thank you!; Includes positive and negative photostats (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Music II, Holograph score; 1 v. (unpaged); Sketchbook of chorales, harmonic exercises, and songs for student work at Harvard University, 1894-1997.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 1, item 17)
    - My horror, Holograph piano-vocal score; [2] p. (Box-folder 6/10)
    - My plan, Holograph piano-vocal score; [3] p. (Box-folder 6/11)
    - My red hair, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; [2] p. (Box-folder 6/12)
    - The mystery See also: Unidentified sketches, miscellaneous (Mfm.# 5/66), Holograph piano-vocal score; [3] p.; On p. 1: May 1915 (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Night songs. Slumber-song; arr. see: Slumber song. 1943
    - Norse lullaby, Holograph piano-vocal score; 3 p.; On p. 1: Copyright 1895 by H. B. Stevens (Box-folder 6/14)
    - The odalisque, Holograph piano-vocal score; 5 p.; On p. 1: January '16 (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Oil and vinegar; for jazz orchestra. 1926, Holograph full score; 29 p.; At end: 6/25/26; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 18)
    - On a screen, Holograph piano-vocal score; 2 p.; see ML96.C274
    - Patterns. 1930-1932, Holograph full score; 41 p.; At end: Begun Mar.-April 1930. Completed May-July 1932.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 19)
    - The penitent, Holograph piano-vocal score, incomplete; [1] p.; On p. 1: August 26th - '20 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Le petit cimetière, Holograph piano-vocal score; [3] p.; At end: March 1923; Includes negative photostat of first page of music (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Le petit cimetière, Holograph piano-vocal score; 3 p.; At end: Sept. '34 (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Le petit cimitière [and] Les cheminées rouges, Photocopy of holograph score, with composer's corrections; 3, 6 p.; At end: 11/14/34; see ML96.C274 (Box-folder 6/18)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 47)
    - Petite suite, Reproduced from copyist's piano score; 5 p. (Box-folder 6/19)
    - A pilgrim vision, Holograph full score; 35 p.; On p. 1: September 1920; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 20)
    - Polonaise Americaine See also: Unidentified sketches, miscellaneous (Mfm.# 5/58), Holograph piano score; [3] p.; On p. 1: Dec. 1912 (Box-folder 6/20)
    - The pools of peace, Holograph piano-vocal score; [2] l.; At end: Dec. 1934; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 48)
    - The pools of peace, Copyist's piano-vocal score; [3] p. (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Prelude and fugue, Holograph piano score; [3] p. (Box-folder 6/22)
    - A protest, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; [2] p. (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Quintet, piano & strings, Holograph score in pencil; 43 p.; see ML29c.C3
      MUSIC 1 (reel 1770)
    - Quintet, piano & strings, Holograph score in ink (33 p.) and reproduced copyist's manuscript parts; On t.p.: Original work written at Algiers, Feb.-Mar. '33. First played at Coolidge Festival, Pittsfield, Mass. ('33); At end: Beverly, Chicago, Carmel, '46-'47; see ML29c.C3
      MUSIC 1 (reel 1771)
    - Quintet, piano & strings, Holograph full score of opening pages; 4 p.; On t.p.: To Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge. Algiers 2/8/34.; At end: 3/24/34; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 21)
    - Quintet, piano & strings, Ozalid of holograph full score, revised version, with holograph pasteovers; 33 p.; At end, in ink: Beverly, Chicago, Carmel, '46-'47 (Box-folder 6/24)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 22)
    - The road that leads me home; arr. see The home road
    - Schifferlied, Copyist's piano-vocal score; [3] p. (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Sea drift, Holograph full score; 30 p.; At end: Eze-Pride's Crossing. Feb.-Sep. 1933.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 23)
    - Sea drift, Photocopy of holograph full score; 30 p.; see ML96.5.C33
    - Sea drift, Holograph condensed score; 12 p.; On t.p.: Original sketch. 1933.; At end: Eze-Prides' '33; Inserted: holograph sketch in pencil, [2] p.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 24)
    - Sehnsucht, Holograph piano score; [1] p. (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Sehnsucht, Holograph piano score; [1] p.; Includes unidentified piano piece (3 p.) (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Serenade, Reproduced from copyist's piano score; [4] p. (Box-folder 6/27)
    - The seven ages, Holograph full score; 74 p.; At end: Hobe Sound, Chicago, Beverly, Feb.-July 1945.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 25)
    - Shake your brown feet, honey See also: Jazz boys, Holograph piano-vocal score; [4] p.; Bound with: The cryin' blues ([2] p.), Jazz boys ([3] p.), and That soothin' song ([2] p.); On p. 1: March 1926 (Box-folder 6/28)
    - Silhouettes see: Songs (1913) Les silhouettes; arr.
    - Sketches of an unidentified symphony and Skyscrapers. 1920-1922, Holograph score; 1 v.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 3, item 37)
    - Sketches of the symphony no. 1, The birthday of the infanta, and an unidentified instrumental piece. 191-, Holograph score; 1 v.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 3, item 34)
    - Skyscrapers, Holograph full score; [92] p.; On t. p.: 1923-1924; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 26)
    - Skyscrapers See also: Sketches of an unidentified symphony and Skyscrapers. 1920-1922, Reproduced from holograph full score, with composer's manuscript emendations; 2 scores (54 p. each); see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 27)
    - Sleep ma honey, sleep, Holograph sketch (vocal part only); [1] p. (Box-folder 6/29)
    - Slumber-song. 1943, Holograph full score; 13 p.; Arranged for voice & orchestra; At end: May '43; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 45)
    - Sonata, piano, A major, Holograph piano score and sketches; [12] p. (Box-folder 6/30)
    - Sonata, piano, G minor, Holograph piano score; [23] p.; At top: 1897 (Box-folder 6/31)
    - Sonata, piano, G minor, Copyist's piano score; 9 p., 4 p., 6 p.; On cover: Graduation Exercise, Music Dept., Harvard College, 1897; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 28)
    - Sonata, violin & piano, Holograph score for violin & piano; 35 p. (Box-folder 7/1)
    - Sonata, violin & piano, Copyist's score for violin & piano, with holograph pasteovers; 39 p. (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Sonata, violin & piano, Copyist's violin part, with pencilled emendations by the composer; 14 p.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 29)
    - A song for Illinois, Holograph full score; 12 p.; At end: Jan. 8-17, 1941.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 30)
    - Song of David, Holograph full score, incomplete; 2 p.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 31)
    - Song of faith, Holograph full score; 39 p.; On p. 1: Aug.-Oct. '31; Laid in: typescript of text; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 50)
    - Song of faith, Holograph full score; 40 p.; On t.p.: Revised 1937; Laid in: 2 p. holograph additions (Box-folder 7/3)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 51)
    - Song of faith, Reproduced from holograph, with composer's manuscript revisions and additions, written or pasted in; 39 p.; At end: Revised Feb. '36; see ML96.C274
    - Song of freedom, Holograph full score; 35 p.; At end: Oct.-Dec. '41. Beverly-Chicago.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 52)
    - Song of freedom, Holograph condensed score; 7, 7 p.; At end: Beverly, Oct. '41; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 53)
    - Song of freedom; arr., Holograph piano-vocal score with text underlay; [2], [2] p.; At end: Nov. 41, Beverly - Chicago; see ML96.C274; Includes negative and positive photostats which can be found under ML96.5.C33a + b
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 54)
    - Songs (1913) Les silhouettes; arr., Holograph full score; 11 p.; At end: May '43; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 4, item 55)
    - Songs of silence, Holograph piano-vocal score; [6] p.; Uniform title: Songs (1913) Les silhouettes; arr.; At end: Pride's Crossing, Aug. '34; see ML96.C274
    - Songs of silence, Positive photocopy of holograph score; 2, 3 p.; Uniform title: Songs (1913) Les silhouettes; arr. (Box-folder 7/4)
    - The spider and the ghost of the fly, Holograph piano-vocal score, incomplete; [1] p.; On p. 1: Nov. '14 (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Spring joys, Holograph score; [3] p.; On p. 1: March '16 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Suite for small orchestra, Holograph full score; 28, 51 p. (Box-folder 7/7)
    - Symphony no. 1, Holograph full score, 1916-1917 version; 1 v. (various pagings); On verso of t.p.: Sermons in stones; At head of p. [1]: Begun July 31-16; At end: Finished March 6th-17; Includes corrections, 4 p.; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 2, item 32)
    - Symphony no. 1 See also: Sketches of the symphony no. 1, The birthday of the infanta, and an unidentified instrumental piece. 191- (Mfm.# 3/34), Holograph full score, 1940 revised version; 72 p.; On p. 1: Begun 1/18/40; At end: Santa Barbara-Chicago. Jan.-April '40; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 3, item 33)
    - Symphony II, Holograph full score, 1941-1942 version (incomplete); 46 p.; Uniform title: Symphony no. 2; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 3, item 35)
    - Symphony II, Holograph full score, 1947 rev. version, with composer's emendations pasted in; 86 p.; Uniform title: Symphony no. 2; At end: Sunset Hill, Beverly, Mass. July-October '41; see ML96.C274
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 3, item 36)
    - Terre promise, Holograph piano-vocal score; 3 p.; On p. 1: June '13 (Box-folder 7/8)
    - That soothin' song see: Shake your brown feet, honey
    - Thoughts, Holograph piano-vocal score; [2] p.; On p. 1: May '20 (Box-folder 7/9)
    - The thunderstorm, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; [1] p. (Box-folder 7/10)
    - To a young gentleman, Holograph piano-vocal score; [4] p.; On p. 1: January '16 (Box-folder 7/11)
    - To one unknown, Holograph piano-vocal score; [4] p. (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Treat me nice, Miss Mandy Jane, Holograph piano-vocal score; [3] p. (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Triste était mon ame, Holograph piano-vocal score; [3] p. (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Triste était mon ame, Holograph piano-vocal sketch; [4] p. (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Triste était mon ame, Copyist's piano-vocal score; 4 p. (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Twilight reverie, Holograph piano score; [4] p.; On p. 1, at bottom: Copyright 1894 by Miles & Thompson, M. & T. 572-4 (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Two little pieces, Copyist's score for violin and piano; 7 p., 9 p. (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Unidentified harmonic exercises, canons, fugues, etc., Holograph sketches; various pagings (Box-folder 7/17-18)
    - Unidentified instrumental works, Holograph sketches and score fragments for various chamber and orchestral instrumental combinations; various pagings (Box-folder 8/1)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 3, item 38;5/67)
    - Unidentified piano works, Holograph scores and sketches; various pagings (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Unidentified sketches, miscellaneous, Holograph sketches; various pagings (Box-folder 8/3-7)
    - Unidentified works for violin & piano, Holograph score for violin & piano, incomplete; 12 p. (Box-folder 8/3-7)
    - Unidentified works for violin & piano, Holograph scores for violin & piano, incomplete; [2], [3] p. (Box-folder 8/8)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 5, item 64)
      MUSIC 1856 (reel 5, item 58;5/64)
    - Die vier Jahreszeiten, Holograph piano-vocal score; [6] p. (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Die vier Jahreszeiten, Holograph piano-vocal score, incomplete; [2] p. (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Die vier Jahreszeiten, Holograph sketch; [4] p. (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Die vier Jahreszeiten, Holograph piano-vocal score in purple pencil; [10] p. (Box-folder 8/9a)
    - Die vier Jahreszeiten, Copyist's piano-vocal score; 9 p. (Box-folder 8/11)
    - Waltz, Holograph piano score (primo part only) [purple clefs]; [5 p.] (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Water colors, Holograph piano-vocal score, incomplete; 4 p. (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Water-colours; Chinese tone poems for small orchestra and mezzo-soprano not present, Holograph full score; 26 p.; Uniform title: Water colors; arr.; see ML96.C274
    - When the night comes, Holograph piano-vocal score, incomplete; [2] p. (Box-folder 8/14)
    - When you unfold the red, red rose, Copyist's score; 2 p. (Box-folder 8/15)
    - Worlds, Holograph score; 2 p.; At end: Dec. 1934 (Box-folder 8/16)
    - The Wrigley wriggle, Copyist's score[?] for violin & piano with holograph signature; [2] p.; On verso: Spain by Jerom Levy (violin and piano parts); [2] p. (Box-folder 8/17)
    - Young man chieftan, Photostats (positive and negative) of holograph score; 4 p.; At end: January 1929 (Box-folder 8/18)
  - Printed Music, 1904-1951 (Box 8-9)
    Arranged alphabetically by composer name.
    - Alpaerts, Flor (Box-folder 8/19)
      - James Ensor suite Brussels: Huis Schott, 1951., Bound reproduction of manuscript
    - Carpenter, John Alden
      - Frei erfundener Canon, Printer's proofs, p. 200-202; Includes: Ziehn, Bernard. Variation des Canons von John A. Carpenter. (Box-folder 8/20)
      - Sea Drift. New York: G. Schirmer, 1936 (Box-folder 8/21)
      - Skyscrapers. A ballet of modern American life. Orchestral score, condensed concert version. New York: G. Schirmer, 1927, Red and blue annotations. (2 copies); Laid in: Cuts for concert performance (typewritten) and table of durations (manuscript) (Box-folder 9/1-2)
      - Song of faith. New York: G. Schirmer, 1939, Pl. no. 35560. (Box-folder 9/3)
      - Song of freedom. New York: G. Schirmer, 1942 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Carpenter, John Alden and Rue Carpenter
      - When little boys sing. Chicago: A. C. McClurg & Co., 1904 (Box-folder 9/5)
    - Guilbert, Yvette (compiler) (Box-folder 9/6)
      - Chansons de la vieille France. Paris: Librairie Félix Juven, undated, Harmonized by Maurice Duhamel.
    - Honegger, Arthur (Box-folder 9/7)
      - Rugby Paris: Editions Maurice Senart, 1929, Holograph dedication to Madame Ellen Borden.
    - Spalding, Walter R. (Box-folder 9/8)
      - Blessed are they that dwell in Thy house, op. 10. Boston: Arthur P. Schmidt, 1937, Holograph dedication: to John with greetings from Walter.
- Photographs and Artwork, 1891-1961 (Box 3, 10-11)
  Of particular note are the numerous photographs and watercolors of the sets and costumes of Carpenter's stage productions. These include photographs of the shadow puppets from Krazy Kat and of both stage designs and stagings of the Birthday of the Infanta. In addition, there are numerous ink and watercolor sketches by Robert Edmund Jones of costume designs from Birthday of the Infanta. Two charcoal drawings of Carpenter in the collection are also by Jones.
  Arranged by subject.
  - John Alden Carpenter alone (Box-folder 3/33, 10/3)
  - John Alden Carpenter and others (Box-folder 3/34, 10/3a)
  - Family of John Alden Carpenter (Box-folder 3/35)
  - Productions:
    - Birthday of the Infanta [production stills, set designs] (Box-folder 10/4)
    - Krazy Kat [production stills] (Box-folder 3/36, 10/4a)
    - Skyscrapers (Box-folder 3/37)
    - Birthday of the Infanta - Sketches for costumes (pencil, ink and paint) (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Robert Edmund Jones. 2 portraits of John Alden Carpenter (charcoal) (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Santa Claus graphic (in color, printed on board (oversize)) (Box-folder 11/1)
- Certificates and Honors, 1921-1961 (Box 10-11)
  Carpenter was a highly successful composer in his day, being named a Knight of the French Legion of Honor (1921) and receiving such honors as the Gold Medal of the National Institute of Arts and Letters. He also received honorary degrees from Harvard University, Northwestern University, the University of Wisconsin, and the American Conservatory of Music.
  Arranged by genre.
  - Degree certificates from:
    - American Conservatory of Music, Chicago, IL (oversize) (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, MA (oversize) (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Northwestern University, Chicago, IL (Box-folder 10/7)
    - University of Wisconsin, Madison, WI (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Membership certificates from:
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, Boston, MA (Box-folder 10/7)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, New York, NY (Box-folder 10/7)
  - Honors from:
    - French Legion of Honor (oversize) (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Unidentified (Slavic language) (oversize) (Box-folder 11/5)
- Programs, 1913-1961 (Box 3)
  Programs of performances.
  - Programs, 1913-1961 (formerly in scrapbooks) (Box-folder 3/38)
- Scrapbooks, 1900-1961 (Box 11-12)
  Scrapbooks (oversize) which include letters, telegrams, programs, photographs, and clippings.
  - 1900-1933 (Box 12)
  - 1914-1942 (Box-folder 11/6)
  - 1943-1961 (Box-folder 11/7)
- Clippings, 1891-1961 (Box 10)
  Miscellaneous clippings from newspapers and other periodicals.
  Arranged by format.
  - Miscellaneous clippings from newspapers and other periodicals (Box-folder 10/8)